Guide to the Picture File, 1700s-1980s and undated RL.01025
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- People Series, 1700s-1970s; 1
  - Ravoninahitriniarivo, Prime Minister of Madagascar, standing, in regalia, and smaller card of unidentified individual, seated, 1880s, 2 carte-des-visites photographs (Box 58, Folder M1802)
  - Recumbent Figure of General R. E. Lee, 1875, card photograph (Box 42)
  - Reese, Lizette Wordsworth, 1896 Sept. and undated, 2 card photographs (Box 30, Folder M1480)
  - Reeves, John (circa 1752-1829), 1798 July 1, engraving (Box 30, Folder M1481)
  - Rehder, Jessie, 1961, black-and-white photograph (Box 30, Folder M1482)
  - Rembrandt van Rijn or Ryn (1606-1669), 1800s, engraving (Box 30, Folder M1483)
  - Remenyi, Eduard, 1897 May 15, card photograph (Box 30, Folder M1484)
  - Research Triangle officials grouped around plans for the RTP: Governor Luther Hodges, Karl Robbins (New York City), and seven other men, circa 1965, Black-and-white 8x10 inch photograph; damaged by water exposure and rust, top edge. Photocopied caption label partly illegible. Please handle with care. (Box 58, Folder M1825)
  - Revels, H. R. - Senator from Mississippi, 1800s, engraving (Box 42)
  - Revolutionary Generals, 1800s, engraving (Box 30, Folder M1485)
    Depicts portraits of five Revolutionary War Generals from South Carolina.
  - Reynolds, Joshua Jones, 1800s, engraving (Box 30, Folder M1486)
  - Reynolds, William Neal, 1900s, card photograph (Box 42)
  - Rice, James Henry, Jr., 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1487)
    Transferred from Rice Papers.
  - Ridley, Nicholas (circa 1500-1555), 1827 Jan. 1, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1488)
  - Riel, Louis, 1886, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1489)
  - Rigsbee, J (ohn) V., undated, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1490)
  - Ringgold, Samuel, 1848 and 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1491)
  - Ringgold, Samuel, death of, 1848, colored engraving (Box 45)
  - Ripley, William Y. W. and family, 1862 and 1800s, 4 card photographs and 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 31, Folder M1492.1)
  - Ripley, William Y. W. and family, 1888 June 13, circa 1886 and 1800s, 3 card photographs, 1 tintype, and 6 black-and-white photographs (Box 31, Folder M1492.2)
  - Ripley, William Y. W. and family, 1888 June 13, circa 1886 and 1800s, 2 card photographs, 5 tintypes and 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 31, Folder M1492.3)
  - Ripley, William Y. W. and family, 1916 Aug. 9, 1900s and 1800s, 4 tintypes and 4 black-and-white photographs (Box 31, Folder M1492.4)
  - Ritchie, Thomas, 1800s, engraving (Box 42)
  - Roberts, Frederick Sleigh, First Earl Roberts, undated, postcard (Box 31, Folder M1494)
  - Roberts, Henry, 1800s, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1495)
  - Rodin, Auguste, undated, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1496)
    Transferred from the Francis Warrington Dawson II Papers. Photograph signed by Auguste Rodin.
  - Rodney, George Brydges, First Baron Rodney (1719-1792), 1829 May 1, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1497)
  - Rodney, Henry W., 1932 Feb., black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1498)
  - Roebuck, John Arthur, 1800s, engraving (Box 45)
  - Rogers, Samuel, 1822, Aug. 16, engraving (Box 42)
  - Rogers, William Allen, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1499)
  - Romaine, William, Rev., undated, engraving (Box 42)
  - Roosevelt and Lincoln, 1905, engraving (Box 42)
  - Roosevelt, Anna Eleanor (Roosevelt), 1951, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1500)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1918 and 1900s, 1 card photograph and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1501)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1968, color photo (Box 56)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, and family, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1502)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, undated, color photo (Box 46)
    Taken from Fortune Magazine.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1944, black-and-white lithograph (Box 59)
    Lithograph by Samuel J. Woolf after his portrait, which is held by the National Portrait Gallery.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, circa 1930, black-and-white photograph (Box 59)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1908, 1906, and 1900s, 1 black-and-white photograph and 2 handbills (Box 31, Folder M1503)
    The handbills are from the Journal of the American Irish Historical Society, Vol. VI and X.
  - Rosecrans, William Starke, 1863 and 1800s, 3 engravings (Box 31, Folder M1504)
  - Rosser, Thomas LaFayette, 1800s, 1 card photograph and 1 engraving (Box 31, Folder M1505)
    The engraving is from Charles E. Jones' scrapbook.
  - Rouss, Charles Broadway, 1800s, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 31, Folder M1506)
  - Rubens, Peter Paul (1577-1640), 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1507)
  - Ruffin, Thomas, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1508)
    Includes signature of Thomas Ruffin.
  - Russell, Irwin, 1800s, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1509)
  - Russell, John, 1869, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1510)
    John Russell was the "founder and proprietor of Russell's Magazine (1857-1860)."
  - Russell, Lord John, First Earl Russell, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1511)
  - Russell, Lord John, First Earl Russell, 1800s, engraving (Box 42)
  - Russell, Lord John, First Earl Russell, 1800s, engraving (Box 45)
  - Russell, Sir William Howard, 1800s and undated, 1 card photograph and 1 clipping (Box 31, Folder M1512)
  - Rutledge, Edward, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1513)
  - Rutledge, John, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1514)
  - Ryan, P. J., 1895 October 1, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1515)
  - Sale, Sir Robert Henry, 1846 March, engraving (Box 45)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1900s, handbill (Box 31, Folder M1518)
  - Sanders, George [Nicholas], 1800s, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1519)
  - Sandidge, John Milton, 1800s, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1520)
  - Santayana, George, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1521)
  - Sanzio, Raffaello, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1493)
  - Sargent, D. A., undated, card photograph (Box 42)
    Transferred from the Wilbur Wade Card Papers.
  - Sarmiento, oleo [oil painting] de Eugenia Bel[?], 1938 Sept. 11, color illustration (Box 31, Folder M1522)
    Transferred from the Alice (Houston) Luigi Mss. Unidentified painter and subject.
  - Saunders, Rebecca Vasser (Howard), undated, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1523)
  - Sawmill(?) Workers, 1888 June, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1524)
  - Scales, Dabney Minor, 1863, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1525)
  - Schenck, Robert Cumming, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1526)
  - Schiller, von, Johann Christoph Friedrich, 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 31, Folder M1527)
  - Schrader, Hermann Henri-Chretien, 1800s, lithograph (Box 31, Folder M1528)
  - Scott, Robert H., 1800s, engraving (Box 45)
  - Scott, Winfield, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1529)
  - Scott, Winfield, 1800s, 4 engravings (Box 31, Folder M1530)
  - Scrughman, G. R., 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1531)
  - Seddon, James Alexander, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1532)
    Includes signature of James Alexander Seddon.
  - Semmes, A. J., undated, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1533)
  - Semmes, Paul I., 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1534)
  - Semmes, Raphael, 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 31, Folder M1535)
  - Semmes, Raphael, 1800s, engraving (Box 46)
  - Semple, Robert S., undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1536)
    Reproduction of a charcoal sketch.
  - Sepida, de, Juan Gina (1490-1574), undated, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1537)
  - Sergeant, U.S. Army Colored Troops, circa 1860s, colored tintype (Box 29, Folder M1371)
  - Settle, Thomas Lee, 1800s, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1538)
  - Seward, William Henry, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1539)
    Negative available. Includes signature of William H. Seward.
  - Seymour, Horatio, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1540)
  - [Seymour, Jane, Third Queen of Henry VIII], 1829 June 1, engraving (Box 46)
  - Sforza, Carlo, Count, 1933 March, black-and-white photograph (Box 31, Folder M1541)
  - Shaffer, A. W., 1800s, card photograph (Box 31, Folder M1542)
  - Shakespeare, William, undated, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1543)
  - Shakespearian Actors Collection, 1789 June-1792 Aug. 7 and undated, 7 engravings (Box 32, Folder M1544.2)
  - Shakespearian Actors Collection, 1819 Oct. 1, 1790 Apr. 1 and undated, 6 engravings (Box 32, Folder M1544.1)
    First item is an illustration attached to Bell's Court and Fashionable Magazine -- 1819 Sept.
  - Shaler, Alexander, 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1545)
  - Shaw, George Bernard, and Henderson, Archibald, 1900s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 32, Folder M1546)
  - Sheftall, Moses, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 32, Folder M1547)
  - Shelby, Isaac, 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1548)
  - Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1800s, 1909 Apr. and undated, 2 card photographs and 2 engravings (Box 32, Folder M1549)
    One of the photographs was transferred from the Edward Wilkinson Kinsley Mss. One engraving transferred from the John M. Gould Mss.
  - Sherman, Roger, 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1550)
  - Sherman, William Tecumseh, 1800s, 1 clipping, 3 engravings, and 1 card photograph (Box 32, Folder M1551.1)
    The clipping was transferred from Charles E. Jones' scrapbook.
  - Sherman, William Tecumseh, 1905, 1874 and 1800s, 1 clipping, 2 engravings, and 1 black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 32, Folder M1551.2)
    The illustration is from Vol. IV of "History of the United States of America" by Henry William Elson. The clipping was transferred from Charles E. Jones' scrapbook.
  - Sherwood, Philip H., Jr., undated, color illustration (Box 46)
  - Shield, James, 1862, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1552)
  - Shook, Alfred M., undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 32, Folder M1553)
  - Sidney, Sir Philip (1554-1586), 1829 May 1, engraving (Box 46)
  - Signers of the Constitution, 1887-1888 and 1800s, 32 engravings (Box 32, Folder M1555)
  - Signers of the Declaration of Independence [North Carolina], 1903, black-and-white illustration (Box 32, Folder M1556)
    From "The Writings of Thomas Jefferson," Memorial Edition, Andrew A. Lipscomb, editor-in-chief.
  - Sigourney, Lydia Huntley, 1873 and 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 32, Folder M1557)
  - Silliman, Benjamin, 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1558)
  - Simmons, Furnifold McLendel, undated, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 32, Folder M1559)
  - Simmons, Furnifold McLendel, undated, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1560)
    Includes possibly authentic signature of Furnifold McLendel Simmons.
  - Simmons, Furnifold McLendel, undated, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 20)
  - Simms, William Gilmore, 1861 and 1840, 3 engravings (Box 32, Folder M1561)
  - Simons, James, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 32, Folder M1562)
    Some color has been added to the photograph.
  - Simpson, W. M., 1800s, card photograph (Box 42)
  - Sims, W. S., Admiral U. S. N., 1919 May, black-and-white photograph (Box 32, Folder M1563)
    Includes W. S. Sims' signature.
  - Singleton, Spyers, circa 1860s, black-and-white photograph (Box 32, Folder M1564)
  - Sir Walter Scott Bart., 1833 Sept., engraving (Box 42)
  - Sitting Bull, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1104)
  - Slattery, Harry Augustus, 1900s, 25 black-and-white photographs (Box 32, Folder M1565)
  - Sloan, John Trimmer, undated, card photograph (Box 32, Folder M1566)
  - Slocum, Henry Warner, 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1567)
  - Smets, A. A., 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 32, Folder M1568)
  - Smith, Alfred Emanuel, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 32, Folder M1569)
  - Smith, Charles Emory, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 32, Folder M1570)
  - Smith, E. Kirby, 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1571)
  - Smith, Gustavus Woodson, 1800s, 3 engravings (Box 32, Folder M1572)
    The smallest engraving is from Charles E. Jones' scrapbook.
  - Smith, John (1794-1831), 1832, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1573)
    Part of the Frank Baker Collection of Wesleyan and British Methodism.
  - Smith, John Blair, undated, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1574)
  - Smith, John Walker, undated, card photograph (Box 32, Folder M1575)
  - Smith, R. Thursfield, undated, card photograph (Box 32, Folder M1576)
  - Smith, Samuel Stanhope, undated, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1577)
  - Smith, Seba, 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1578)
    Journalist, humorist. Wrote columns with pen name Major Jack Downing.
  - Smith, Sir William Sidney, 1808 Feb. 1, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1579)
  - Smith, Stephens Calhoun, 1800s, card photograph (Box 32, Folder M1580)
  - Smith, W. J., 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1581)
  - Smith, William (1797-1887), 1800s, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1583)
  - Smith, William, 1880, engraving (Box 32, Folder M1582)
  - Smith, Willis, circa 1930s, black-and-white photo (Box 57)
    Of Raleigh, N.C.
  - Smuts, Jan Christian, 1900s, card photograph (Box 46)
  - Snow, H. N., 1900s, card photograph (Box 32, Folder M1584)
  - Snowden, Yates, circa 1928 and undated, 1 card photograph and 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 32, Folder M1585)
    From the Wm. R., James C., and Robert R. Hemphill Mss.
  - Socialist Party of America Oklahoma leaders, circa 1915, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 33, Folder M1586)
    Both these photographs have negatives available.
  - Society of the Army and Navy of the Confederate states in the state of Maryland, 189-, black-and-white lithograph (Oversize-folder 29)
    Unused certificate for membership.
  - Solberg, Thorvald, 1900s, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 33, Folder M1587)
  - Somers, John, Baron Somers (1651-1716), 1831 Nov. 1 and 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 33, Folder M1588)
  - Somerset, Fitzroy James Henry, First Baron Raglan, 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1589)
  - Somerset, Henry Charles, Duke of Beaufort, 1829, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1590)
  - Somerset, Henry, First Marquis of Worcester, 1827 Dec. 1, engraving (Box 46)
  - Soong, Charles Jones and Mamie Soong, 1886 Mar. 29 and 1800s, 3 card photographs and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 33, Folder M1591)
  - Soule Pierre, circa 1849-1850 and 1853-1857, 1 engraving and 1 clipping (Box 33, Folder M1592)
  - South Carolina Legislature (Radical Members), 1800s, card photograph (Box 42)
  - Southgate, James Haywood, 1900s, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 42)
  - Southgate, James Haywood, 1946, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 46)
    Illustration is part of a poem, "Marse Jim," by D.W. Newsom. Includes biographical and historical background note.
  - Southgate, James, undated, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 20)
  - Spangenberg, Aug. Gottlieb, 1800s, engraving (Box 46)
  - Spencer, George John, Second Earl Spencer (1758-1834), 1830 and 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 33, Folder M1594)
  - Spotswood, Alexander and Anne Butler (Brayne), undated, 2 card photographs (Box 33, Folder M1595)
  - St. Clair, Arthur, 1800s, engraving (Box 31, Folder M1516)
    From the Georgia Historical Society. Includes signature of Arthur St. Clair.
  - St. Memin Collection, undated, 48 black-and-white photographs (Box 31, Folder M1517)
    Photographs of portraits from the Marmaduke Floyd Collection.
  - St. Memin, 1900, black-and-white mezzotint (Box 57)
    Mezzotint by Max Rosenthal, signed by the artist.
  - Stanley, Sir William (d. 1495), 1836, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1596)
  - Steele, Sir Richard (1672-1729), 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1597)
  - Steinberger, Justus, circa 1870s, card photograph (Box 33, Folder M1598)
  - Stephens, Alexander Hamilton, 1867 and 1800s, 5 engravings, 1 black-and-white photographic illustration and 2 card photographs (Box 33, Folder M1599)
    Includes items from the C. C. Clay Papers, J. J. Crittenden Mss., and from Jones: Biographical Sketches of the Delegates from Georgia to the Continental Congress.
  - Stephens, Alexander Hamilton, et al., 1866, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1600)
    Transferred from the Marmaduke Floyd collection. From Edward A. Pollard's "The Lost Cause...," N.Y., E.B. Treat and Co., 1866.
  - Stephens, Linton, 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1601)
    Includes a possibly authentic signature of Linton Stephens.
  - Stephens, Sir Philip, First Baronet, 1798 Apr. 5, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1602)
  - Stephenson, Wendell Holmes, circa 1963 and 1900s, 5 black-and-white photographs (Box 33, Folder M1603)
  - Stevenson, Vernon K., 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1604)
  - Stewart, Alexander P., 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 33, Folder M1605)
  - Stewart, Lord James, Earl of Mar, and afterwards of Moray, 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1606)
  - Stewart, Robert, Viscount Castlereagh and Second Marquis of Londonderry, 1814 Apr. 21, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1607)
  - Stoddard, Richard Henry, undated, card photograph (Box 33, Folder M1608)
  - Stout, Samuel Hollingsworth, circa 1860s, black-and-white photograph (Box 33, Folder M1609)
  - Stovall, M. A., 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1610)
  - Stowe, Harriet Elizabeth (Beecher), 1800s, engraving (Box 46)
  - Stowe, Harriet Elizabeth (Beecher), 1800s and undated, 1 handbill (Box 33, Folder M1611)
  - Stratton, Charles Sherwood (Tom Thumb), 2 card photographs (Box 33, Folder M1612)
  - Strother, David Hunter, 1879, sketch (Box 33, Folder M1613)
    Sketch drawn by Strother himself. Transferred from an addition to the Clara Victoria (Dargan) Maclean Papers.
  - Stuart, J. E. B., 1800s, 3 engravings and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 33, Folder M1614)
  - Stuart, Marie [Mary], Queen of Scots, undated, 2 engravings (Box 33, Folder M1615)
  - Sumner, Charles, 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1616)
  - Sumner, E. V., 1864, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1617)
  - Swanson, Claude Augustine, undated, 2 card photographs (Box 33, Folder M1618)
    The smaller card photograph has a negative available.
  - Swayne, Noah H., 1890, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1619)
  - Swinburne, Algernon Charles, 1800s, 1860-1861, and 1900s, 5 black-and-white photographs, 1 card photograph and 3 black-and-white photographic illustrations (Box 33, Folder M1620)
  - Swinburne, Henry, 1795 and undated, 1 engraving and 1 clipping (Box 33, Folder M1621)
  - Swinburne, Sir John Edward, 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1622)
  - Taft, William Howard, 1911 May 18, and 1911 (no day), 1 black-and-white photographic illustration and 1 card photograph (Box 33, Folder M1638)
    The photograph includes a personal dedication from William Howard Taft. From "The Journal of the American Irish Historical Society, Vol. X, N.Y., 1911."
  - Talbot, Charles, Twelfth Earl and Only Duke of Shrewsbury, 1835 Apr. 1, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1623)
  - Talbott, Sallie Radford (Munford), 1867 June 13, card photograph (Box 33, Folder M1624)
  - Taney, Roger Brooke, undated, card photograph (Box 33, Folder M1625)
  - Tarleton, Banastre, 1782 Mar. and 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 33, Folder M1626)
  - Tasso, Torquato (1534-1595), 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1627)
  - Tattnall, Josiah, 1800s, 2 engravings and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 33, Folder M1628)
    Photograph includes Josiah Tattnall's signature.
  - Taylor, C. C., 1895, card photograph (Box 33, Folder M1629)
  - Taylor, George, undated, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1630)
  - Taylor, James, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 33, Folder M1631)
    Copy of a photograph possessed by Mrs. Nina Adelaide Taylor Matthews of Claremore, Okla.
  - Taylor, Nathaniel W., 1847, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1632)
  - Taylor, Richard, undated, clipping (Box 33, Folder M1633)
  - Taylor, Zachary, 1847, 1863 and 1800s, 6 engravings (Box 33, Folder M1635)
    One of these engravings is from "The Statesman's Manual," by Edwin Williams and Benson J. Lossing, Vol. III. One of these engravings includes Zachary Taylor's signature.
  - Taylor, Zachary, 1858, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1634)
  - Tefft, Israel Keech, 1800s, 2 card photographs (Box 33, Folder M1636)
  - Tefft, Israel Keech, 1800s, card photograph (Box 33, Folder M1637)
    Transferred from the C. C. Jones, Jr. Mss.
  - Telfair, Mary, 1917, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 33, Folder M1639)
    Transferred from the Marmaduke Floyd Collection. Georgia Historical Journal, Vol. I, no. 1, 1917.
  - Temple, Henry John, Third Viscount Palmerston, 1832 and 1820, 3 engravings (Box 33, Folder M1640)
  - Tenants (African Americans), 1800s, 3 black-and-white photographs and 1 card photograph (Box 29, Folder M1372)
    Transferred from the Reuben D. Bowen Mss.
  - Terrell, James W., 1874 May 18, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 33, Folder M1641)
  - Terriss, Ellaline, undated, postcard (Box 33, Folder M1642)
  - Terry, Alfred Howe, 1800s, engraving (Box 33, Folder M1643)
  - Terry, Dame Ellen, undated, postcard (Box 33, Folder M1644)
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1911, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1645)
    Transferred from the Marmaduke Floyd Collection. From Harper's Monthly Magazine, June 1911.
  - The Merry Slave, 1857, color engraving (Box 42)
  - The Right Hon. William Wyndham Grenville, 1815, black-and-white engraving (Box 56)
  - Theodori Bryleodien, undated, engraving (Box 46)
  - Theodosia, 1802, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1646)
  - Thomas, Edward L., 1800s, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1647)
  - Thomas, George Henry, 1800s, 3 engravings (Box 34, Folder M1648)
  - Thomas, James Augustus, 1900s, 4 black-and-white photographs and 1 black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 34, Folder M1649)
  - Thomas, William Holland, 1800s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 34, Folder M1650)
    These photographs of a portrait are duplicates. Includes biographical and historical information
  - Thompson, Edgar, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 34, Folder M1651)
  - Thompson, John Reuben, 1800s, 2 card photographs (Box 34, Folder M1652)
  - Thompson, Merriwether Jeff, 1800s, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 34, Folder M1653)
  - Thornton, Henry T., 1929 Mar., black-and-white photograph (Box 34, Folder M1654)
  - Thorwaldsen, Albert, by John Sartain, for the Eclectic, 1800s, black-and-white engraving (Box 58, Folder M1803)
  - Tilghman, William, 1827, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1655)
  - Tillman, Benjamin Ryan, 1900s, black-and-white photographic illustration, stereograph (Box 34, Folder M1656)
    Transferred from the William Watts Ball Mss.
  - Tillotson, John, undated, engraving (Box 46)
  - Timrod, Henry and William Henry, 1800s, card photograph (Box 34, Folder M1658)
  - Timrod, Henry, undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 34, Folder M1657)
  - Titus Livius, 1800s, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1659)
  - Todd, Thomas, 1889, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1660)
  - Tomline, Sir George Pretyman, undated, engraving (Box 46)
  - Tommy Fire Cloud, a young Hampton brave, 1886 Dec., card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1105)
  - Tomo Chachi Mico, undated, lithograph (Box 34, Folder M1661)
  - Tompkins, Christopher, undated, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 34, Folder M1662)
  - Tompkins, Daniel D., 1800s, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1663)
  - Toms, Clinton W., 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 34, Folder M1664)
  - Tooke, John Horne, 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 34, Folder M1665)
    Original newsprint biographical note photocopied.
  - Toombs, Robert, 1800s, 4 engravings (Box 34, Folder M1666)
  - Torrens, Sir Henry, 1829, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1667)
    Includes possibly authentic signature of Henry Torrens.
  - Torsch, John W., 1800s, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1668)
  - Townshend, Lady, 1806 June 1, engraving (Box 34, Folder M1669)
  - Tracy, Benjamin Franklin, 1900s, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 34, Folder M1670)